<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>White House.gov Blog Feed</title>
    <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog</link>
    <description></description>
    <language>en</language>
        <item>
 <title>#visitUS: Americans share what makes their hometown a great place to visit</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/22/visitus-americans-share-what-makes-their-hometown-great-place-visit</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	President Obama was in Disney World to <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/19/president-obama-promotes-tourism-disney-world">announce steps</a> his administration is taking to boost tourism and travel in the United States, and Americans from all over the country added their voice to the discussion on why this is such a great country to visit on <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/search/%23visitus">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://Facebook.com/whitehouse">Facebook</a> and <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/webform/what-makes-your-hometown-great-place-visit">WhiteHouse.gov</a>. From the Lobster Capital to Rocket City,&nbsp;people around the country shared the must-see destinations in their hometown. Have a look at some of the responses below or on <a href="http://storify.com/whitehouse/where-americans-think-tourists-should-visitus">Storify</a>, then tell us about your city or town.</p>
<p></p><p>[<a href="http://storify.com/whitehouse/where-americans-think-tourists-should-visitus" target="_blank">View the story "#visitUS: What makes your hometown a great place to visit?" on Storify</a>]</p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/45">Economy</category>
 <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 19:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/45&quot;&gt;Kori Schulman&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">114325 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Weekly Address: America is Open for Business</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/21/weekly-address-america-open-business</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	President Obama tells the American people about a series of steps he&#39;s taken without the help of Congress to grow the economy and create jobs -- including a new strategy aimed at boosting tourism introduced this week. In next week&#39;s State of the Union Address, the President will outline his blueprint for creating an economy built to last.</p>
<p>
	</p>
<p>
	&nbsp;<a href="/the-press-office/2012/01/21/weekly-address-creating-jobs-boosting-tourism">Transcript</a> | <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/WeeklyAddress/2012/012112-DQAZBC/012112_WeeklyAddress.mp4">Download mp4</a> | <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/WeeklyAddress/2012/012112-DQAZBC/012112_WeeklyAddress.mp3">Download mp3</a></p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/16">The President</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/38">Weekly Address</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/45">Economy</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/econ-jobs">Econ. Jobs</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/econ-we-cant-wait">Econ. We Cant Wait</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/economy">Economy</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/sotu-2012">SOTU 2012</category>
 <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/3336903&quot;&gt;Matt Compton&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">114307 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>America Is Open for Business </title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/20/america-open-business</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	Yesterday, President Obama traveled to Disney World to announce new initiatives to significantly increase travel and tourism in the United States.&nbsp;The fact is, each year, tens of millions of people from around the world visit the U.S.&nbsp; In 2010, the travel and tourism industry generated over $134 billion dollars for the American economy.&nbsp; It supported 7.5 million jobs in 2010. The President wants these numbers to grow.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	He traveled down to the Magic Kingdom yesterday to deliver one message: America is open for business.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	The President wants the United States to be the number one tourist destination in the world.&nbsp;It&rsquo;s good for businesses and it&rsquo;s good for the economy as a whole. More tourists means more money spent in our cities and towns across the nation. It means more people will be renting cars, dining out, checking into hotels and checking out the sights and sounds of America.&nbsp; That means more jobs.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	The President will continue to do everything he can to rebuild an economy where hard work pays off, where responsibility is rewarded, and where anyone can make it if they try.&nbsp;He wants to restore the economic security for the middle class and those trying to reach it.&nbsp;Yesterday&rsquo;s announcement was an important step to put folks back to work, and he&rsquo;ll keep at it and continue to do everything he can to strengthen the economy.</p>
<p>
	The President&rsquo;s announcement will have an impact on communities all over the United States.&nbsp;Let&rsquo;s take a look at the coverage from local media outlets across the country:</p>
<p>
	Orlando Sentinel &ndash; <a href="http://www.orlandosentinel.com/the-daily-disney/os-obama-disney-tourism-20120118,0,4715284.story">Obama at Disney: &#39;America is open for business&#39;</a></p>
<p>
	President Barack Obama promised Florida&#39;s tourism industry Thursday that he intends to open the door wider to international tourists and was greeted with cheers in a state where increased foreign visitors are seen as one of the best hopes for future jobs.</p>
<p>
	Even Obama critic U.S. Rep. John Mica, R-Winter Park, welcomed the presidential directives, if only with a &quot;what took him so long?&quot; spin.</p>
<p>
	Arizona Republic &ndash; <a href="http://www.azcentral.com/arizonarepublic/news/articles/2012/01/19/20120119obama-touting-tourism-jobs.html">Obama touting tourism for jobs</a></p>
<p>
	President Barack Obama said Thursday that he wants to create more jobs by drawing more international tourists to the United States, a plan White House officials said would especially benefit states like Arizona, home to the Grand Canyon and other national parks.</p>
<p>
	Creating jobs has become a central part of Obama&#39;s re-election campaign. On Wednesday, Obama will visit the Valley as part of a five-state tour to build upon themes -- likely jobs and economic development -- that he will emphasize Tuesday in his annual address to Congress.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/20/america-open-business" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/16">The President</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/45">Economy</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/econ-business-america">Econ. Business in America</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/econ-jobs">Econ. Jobs</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/economy">Economy</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 19:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Josh Earnest </dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">114217 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>State of the Union 2012: We Want to Hear From You</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/20/state-union-2012-we-want-hear-you</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	Mark your calendars! Next Tuesday January 24, President Obama will present the annual State of the Union Address at 9 pm EST, and all week long, the White House wants to hear from concerned citizens on the topics that most matter to you.</p>
<p>
	Once again, we will be streaming an enhanced version of the speech that features graphics, data and stats that highlight the issues the President is discussing&nbsp;on <a href="https://whitehouse.gov/sotu">Whitehouse.gov/sotu</a>. We will also live stream that broadcast through the <a href="https://apps.facebook.com/whitehouselive/">White House Live App</a> on <a href="http://Facebook.com/whitehouse">Facebook</a>,&nbsp;<a href="http://YouTube.com/whitehouse">YouTube</a>&nbsp;and our new&nbsp;<a href="https://plus.google.com/b/105479712798762608629/105479712798762608629/posts">Google+</a>&nbsp;page.</p>
<p>
	</p>
<p>
	Starting immediately after the speech and continuing through the rest of the week, senior White House officials will hear from you about the state of our union. President Obama is committed to creating a system of transparency, public participation, and collaboration using social media and other online resources to engage citizens across America on your highest priorities.</p>
<p>
	Immediately following the speech, we&rsquo;ll be streaming an online panel live from the White House. The panel of senior advisors -- Mark Zuckerman, White House Deputy Director of the Domestic Policy Council; Roberto Rodriguez, Special Assistant to the President for Education Policy; Brian Deese, Deputy Director National Economic Council; Ben Rhodes, Deputy NSA for Strategic Communications and Speechwriting and Jen Palmieri, Deputy White House Communications Director &ndash; will be answering questions about the President&rsquo;s address submitted by citizens via twitter (<a href="https://twitter.com/#!/search/%23whchat">#WHChat</a> &amp; <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/search/%23sotu">#SOTU</a>), <a href="https://plus.google.com/b/105479712798762608629/105479712798762608629/posts">Google+</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/WhiteHouse">Facebook</a> and the in-person audience of tweetup participants.</p>
<p>
	Administration officials will spend Wednesday taking questions on the State of the Union in a day-long&nbsp;<a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2011/07/26/white-house-office-hours">Office Hours</a> marathon, an online question and answer session through Twitter.&nbsp;Josh Earnest, White House Principal Deputy Press Secretary, will be available throughout the day, and Mark Zuckerman, White House Deputy Director of the Domestic Policy Council will be taking questions&nbsp;at 1 pm EST. Dan Pfeiffer, the White House Communications Director, will also participate.</p>
<p>
	Thursday&rsquo;s Office Hours will feature community-focused discussions with policy advisors and experts and Friday will be directed towards specific issues.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	Review the full schedule of events below to learn how you can participate. We hope you will join us at some point next week.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/20/state-union-2012-we-want-hear-you" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/45">Economy</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/education">Education</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/energy-environment">Energy &amp; Environment</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/fiscal-responsibility">Fiscal Responsibility</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/foreign-policy">Foreign Policy</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/health-care">Health Care</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/urban-policy">Urban Policy</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/veterans">Veterans</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/women">Women</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/office-hours">Office Hours</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/sotu-2012">SOTU 2012</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 16:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/475&quot;&gt;Colleen Curtis&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">114049 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>From the Archives: The Inauguration of President Barack Obama</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/20/archives-inauguration-president-barack-obama</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	On this day in 2009, Barack Obama was sworn into office as the 44th President of the United States. Watch him take the oath and deliver his&nbsp;inaugural address below, and read the full transcript <a href="/blog/inaugural-address/">here</a>.</p>
<p>
	</p>
<p>
	At 12:01 that day, the very first post on the White House blog went up. Read it here now: <a href="/blog/change_has_come_to_whitehouse-gov">Change Has Come to WhiteHouse.gov</a>.</p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/16">The President</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 15:59:07 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/3699933&quot;&gt;Megan Slack&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">114193 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The White House Joins Google+</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/20/white-house-joins-google</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	Starting today, we&rsquo;re excited to announce that you can follow the <a href="https://plus.google.com/b/105479712798762608629/105479712798762608629/posts">White House on Google+</a>. On day one, President Obama made clear that this Administration is committed to public engagement and participation. That&rsquo;s why we launched the We the People petitioning tool and why you can find the White House on Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn and other places around the web. These are just some of the ways that we aim to engage with Americans on the issues that matter the most -- and now, we&#39;re pleased to add <a href="http://goo.gl/mzaKd">Google+</a> to this list.</p>
<p>
	On the <a href="https://plus.google.com/b/105479712798762608629/105479712798762608629/posts">White House Google+ page</a>, you&rsquo;ll find news from the blog, behind the scenes photos and videos, plus chances to participate. We hope you&rsquo;ll add your voice to the discussion and share the things you find interesting with people in your circles.</p>
<p>
	One feature we&rsquo;re really excited about are Hangouts, a live multi-person video chat with up to ten&nbsp;participants. The President and First Lady often call the White House &ldquo;The People&rsquo;s House.&rdquo; Well, this is another way we&rsquo;re opening our doors (virtually) to citizens around the country. On our Google+ page, we&rsquo;ll host regular &ldquo;White House Hangouts&rdquo; with administration officials on a range of issues and topics. Some Google+ users will be invited to join the Hangout with the White House and have a conversation with policy experts. But the best part is that even if you&rsquo;re not &ldquo;in&rdquo; the Hangout, you can watch the whole thing live on WhiteHouse.gov, on our Google+ page or on the White House YouTube channel.</p>
<p>
	To kick things off, we want to hear from you about our new page. What else would you like to see from the White House on Google+? Have a great idea for a White House Hangout or thoughts on the types of updates that are most interesting? Let us know on our new <a href="http://goo.gl/mzaKd">Google+ page</a>.</p>
<p>
	So, what are you waiting for? <a href="https://plus.google.com/b/105479712798762608629/105479712798762608629/posts">Add the White House</a> to your circles. We&rsquo;re looking forward to hanging out!</p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/technology">Technology</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 15:43:05 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/45&quot;&gt;Kori Schulman&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">114067 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>West Wing Week: 01/20/12 or &quot;The Time is Always Right to Do What is Right&quot;</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/20/west-wing-week-012012-or-time-always-right-do-what-right</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p><object height="318" width="520"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube-nocookie.com/v/PVd8YneDVek?version=3&amp;showinfo=0&amp;hl=en_US" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><embed allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" height="318" src="http://www.youtube-nocookie.com/v/PVd8YneDVek?version=3&amp;showinfo=0&amp;hl=en_US" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="520" wmode="transparent"></embed></object></p>
<p>
	This week, the President called for government reform through reorganization and a new Cabinet position, honored Martin Luther King, Jr., welcomed the Tuskegee airmen, the King of Jordan, and the 2011 World Series Champs, and traveled to the Magic Kingdom to unveil the latest &ldquo;We Can&rsquo;t Wait&rdquo; action.</p>
<p>
	&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/16">The President</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/45">Economy</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/west-wing-week">West Wing Week</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/3336903&quot;&gt;Matt Compton&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">114025 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Your Ideas for Putting Americans Back to Work </title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/19/your-ideas-putting-americans-back-work</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	Back in November, for the&nbsp;latest installment of the <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2011/02/07/advise-advisor-your-direct-line-white-house">White House&rsquo;s Advise the Advisor series</a>, Deputy Chief of Staff for Policy Nancy-Ann DeParle asked Americans for their <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/photos-and-video/video/2011/11/04/advise-advisor-nancy-ann-deparle">ideas for executive actions</a> or steps that President Obama could take, without waiting for Congress to act, to help out middle class families and small business and put Americans back to work. &nbsp;</p>
<p>
	Over 18,000 people sent in their ideas, both&nbsp;for actions that the Administration can take, as well as ideas for community actions that non-profits, state and local governments, companies and individuals can take to help grow the economy. For the past few months a team of folks at the White House have combed through the comments. However, we didn&rsquo;t just read these submissions and file them away.</p>
<p>
	In fact, Nancy-Ann DeParle called Ira from Glastonbury, Connecticut to discuss his idea to encourage businesses to get involved in youth mentoring and internship programs.&nbsp; Here&#39;s a look at the call:</p>
<p>
	</p>
<p>
	A lot of people like Ira wanted to see us do more to encourage businesses to hire and mentor youth, and this week, the President announced <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2012/01/05/we-cant-wait-white-house-announces-federal-and-private-sector-commitment">Summer Jobs+,</a> &nbsp;a call to action for businesses, non-profits and government to work together to provide pathways to employment for low-income and disconnected youth in the summer of 2012. &nbsp;Summer Jobs+ includes Federal Government and private sector commitments to create 180,000 employment opportunities, with the goal of 250,000 commitments by the start of the summer. &nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/19/your-ideas-putting-americans-back-work" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/45">Economy</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/econ-we-cant-wait">Econ. We Cant Wait</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 22:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Erin Lindsay </dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">113941 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>President Obama Promotes Tourism from Disney World</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/19/president-obama-promotes-tourism-disney-world</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<div class="embed">
	
<div class="clearfix" id="small-node-embed-image-detail">
  <img src="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/imagecache/embedded_img_small/image/image_file/20120119-potus-disney.jpg" alt="President Obama talks tourism at Walt Disney World " title="President Obama talks tourism at Walt Disney World " class="imagecache imagecache-embedded_img_small" width="430" height="652" />  <p>President Barack Obama delivers remarks on a strategy that will significantly help boost tourism and travel during a statement at the Magic Kingdom Theme Park at the Walt Disney World Resort in Orlando, Florida, Jan. 19, 2012.  (Official White House Photo by Sonya N. Hebert)</p>
</div></div>
<p>
	In the United States, tourism is big business. In fact, it&#39;s the number one service that we export. In 2010, we welcomed nearly 60 million international visitors to America, and they helped to boost our economy to the tune of $134 billion.</p>
<p>
	And President Obama thinks we should do even&nbsp;more to boost that trend, which is&nbsp;why he traveled to Walt Disney World in Orlando, Florida. Speaking from Main Street USA, he <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2012/01/19/remarks-president-unveiling-strategy-help-boost-travel-and-tourism">announced</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>
		[Today,] I directed my administration to send me a new national tourism strategy focused on creating jobs. And some of America&rsquo;s most successful business leaders &ndash;- some who are here today &ndash;- have signed up to help. We&rsquo;re going to see how we can make it easier for foreign tourists to find basic information about visiting America. And we&rsquo;re going to see how we can attract more tourists to our national parks. We want people visiting not just Epcot Center, but the Everglades, too. The more folks who visit America, the more Americans we get back to work.&nbsp; It&rsquo;s that simple.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>
	The President said that his goal is to ensure that the United States is the top tourist destination in the world. He announced efforts to expand the Global Entry Program, which makes it easier for frequent visitors to the United States -- who&#39;ve undergone a background check -- to travel in and out of our borders. He told the audience that he&#39;d directed his administration to add additional nations to the list of those whose citizens are allowed to visit America without a tourist visa.</p>
<p>
	And in changing world where the middle class is booming in places like China, India, and Brazil, the President announced steps to make it easier for people from those countries to choose the United States as a place for their vacations:</p>
<blockquote><p>
		[Today] I&rsquo;m directing the State Department to accelerate our ability to process visas by 40 percent in China and in Brazil this year. We&rsquo;re not talking about five years from now or 10 years from now -- this year.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>
	These are all things the President is doing right now -- as part of the <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/economy/jobs/we-cant-wait">We Can&#39;t Wait</a> campaign.</p>
<p>
	Do you think your community is a great place to visit? Tell us about it on Twitter using the hashtag <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/search?q=%23VisitUS">#VisitUS</a>.</p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/16">The President</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/45">Economy</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/econ-jobs">Econ. Jobs</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/econ-we-cant-wait">Econ. We Cant Wait</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/economy">Economy</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 22:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/3336903&quot;&gt;Matt Compton&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">114001 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>One Year After Failed Repeal Effort, Affordable Care Act Continues to Help Americans</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/19/one-year-after-failed-repeal-effort-affordable-care-act-continues-help-americans</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	Like many Americans, Gail Freyer needs health insurance to help her manage her diabetes.&nbsp; For years, she has struggled to find an insurance plan that would accept her with her pre-existing condition &ndash; and with a premium she could afford.&nbsp; Thanks to the Affordable Care Act, Gail was able to enroll in the Pre-Existing Condition Insurance Plan in Arizona.&nbsp; Now, Gail knows she&rsquo;ll be able to access the care she needs to manage her diabetes and stay healthy.</p>
<p>
	This story could have ended very differently if Republicans in the House had their way.&nbsp; One year ago today, on January 19, 2011, the House of Representatives voted to repeal the health reform law, and take us back to the days when insurance companies had the power to decide what care residents of the United States could receive &ndash; allowing them to once again deny coverage to children with pre-existing conditions, cancel coverage when people get sick, and place lifetime or low annual dollar limits on the amount of care people can get, even if they need it.&nbsp; What&rsquo;s more, without the law, insurance companies could overcharge for insurance just to boost their profits. And if House Republicans had gotten their way:</p>
<p>
	&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 2.5 million young adults wouldn&rsquo;t have health insurance.</p>
<p>
	&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 2.65 million seniors would have paid $1.5 billion more for prescription drugs</p>
<p>
	&bull;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 24.2 million seniors would pay for preventive services they are getting for free.</p>
<p>
	Thankfully, the Affordable Care Act is the law of the land and it&rsquo;s helping Gail and millions like her. Check out the <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/repeal_anniversary_fact_sheet.pdf">short report </a>we&rsquo;ve done about some of the Americans who are being helped by the law and what would have happened if the law has been repealed here.</p>
<div class="tag-line">
	Nancy-Ann DeParle is the Assistant to the President and Deputy Chief of Staff.</div>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/45">Economy</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/health-care">Health Care</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 21:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Nancy-Ann DeParle</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">113995 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>America&#039;s First Tourists</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/19/americas-first-tourists</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<div class="embed">
<div class="embed">
		What&#39;s the best place in the world to go on vacation?</div>
<div class="embed">
		&nbsp;</div>
<div class="embed">
		Why the United States, of course. President Obama today unveiled an ambitious plan to make this country the #1 tourist destination in the world. The President was speaking at Walt Disney World in Florida, which is one of the most popular&nbsp;attractions in America, but he wanted to make sure people think about all the other great places worth visiting -- especially the national treasure of our National Parks System. And he speaks from experience, because&nbsp;over the past few years the First Family have been privileged to visit many of this country&#39;s most beautiful&nbsp;destinations:</div>
<div class="embed">
		&nbsp;</div>
<h5 class="embed">
		Acacia State Park, Maine</h5>
<div class="embed">
		
<div class="clearfix" id="small-node-embed-image-detail">
  <img src="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/imagecache/embedded_img_small/image/image_file/acadia.jpg" alt="President Barack Obama and his family hike at Acadia National Park" title="President Barack Obama and his family hike at Acadia National Park" class="imagecache imagecache-embedded_img_small" width="430" height="287" />  <p>President Barack Obama and his family hike on Cadillac Mountain at Acadia National Park in Maine, July 16, 2010.</p>
</div></div>
<h5 class="embed">
		Grand Canyon, Arizona</h5>
</div>
<div class="embed">
	
<div class="clearfix" id="small-node-embed-image-detail">
  <img src="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/imagecache/embedded_img_small/image/image_file/grandcanyon.jpg" alt="President Barack Obama at the Grand Canyon " title="President Barack Obama at the Grand Canyon " class="imagecache imagecache-embedded_img_small" width="430" height="287" />  <p>President Barack Obama looks at the Grand Canyon in Arizona on Aug. 16, 2009. </p>
</div></div>
<p><a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/19/americas-first-tourists" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/16">The President</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/18">The First Lady</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/45">Economy</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 16:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/475&quot;&gt;Colleen Curtis&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">113869 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Vets Descend on Washington for Career Fair and Expo</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/19/vets-descend-washington-career-fair-and-expo</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<div class="embed">
	
<div class="clearfix" id="small-node-embed-image-detail">
  <img src="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/imagecache/embedded_img_small/image/image_file/vets_career_fair_1.jpg" alt="Vets Attend DC Career Fair and Expo " title="Vets Attend DC Career Fair and Expo " class="imagecache imagecache-embedded_img_small" width="430" height="286" />  <p>Veterans and Servicemembers line up to apply for thousands of public and private sector job opportunities at a major career fair hosted by VA.</p>
</div></div>
<p>
	Job opportunities were up for grabs on Wednesday at the <a href="http://www.vaforvets.com/dc/">Veterans Career Fair and Expo</a>&nbsp;in Washington, D.C. Employers representing companies across the private sector, as well as several government agencies, were on site to discuss career and job opportunities to thousands of Veterans from the mid-Atlantic region.</p>
<p>
	The career fair is part of the White House &ldquo;Joining Forces&rdquo; initiative to put qualified Veterans into meaningful employment. VA Secretary Eric Shinseki has made Veteran employment a high priority, and has moved to ensure programs like <a href="http://vaforvets.va.gov/Pages/default.aspx">VA for Vets</a>&nbsp;can help former service members translate their military skills to the civilian workforce.</p>
<p>
	When I asked a recruiter from the National Science Foundation why he felt Veterans made good employees, he looked at me like I asked a silly question. &ldquo;You can&rsquo;t hire anyone better than a Vet,&rdquo; he said.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/19/vets-descend-washington-career-fair-and-expo" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/45">Economy</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/veterans">Veterans</category>
 <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 16:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Alex Horton </dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">113839 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Increasing Energy Security</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/18/increasing-energy-security</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	Ed Note: Read Heather Zichal&rsquo;s editorial in USA Today on the Administration&rsquo;s Announcement on the Keystone XL Pipeline</p>
<p>
	There is a lot of discussion lately about domestic energy production and American energy security. For the Obama Administration, moving towards the goal of energy independence has been a clear priority since day one. When President Obama took office, the United States imported 11 million barrels of oil a day. The President has put forward a plan to cut that by one-third by 2025 by strengthening domestic production of our energy resources, making our homes and buildings more efficient, and transitioning to a wide range of clean energy technologies.</p>
<p>
	When it comes to domestic energy production, the numbers speak for themselves. Since 2008, U.S. oil and natural gas production has increased, while imports of foreign oil have decreased. Here are the facts:&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>
		In 2011, U.S. crude oil production reached its highest level since 2003, increasing by an estimated 90,000 barrels per day (bbl/d) over 2010 levels to 5.57 million bbl/d.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li>
<li>
		U.S. natural gas production grew by an estimated 7.4 percent in 2011&ndash; the largest year-over-year volumetric increase &ndash; and easily eclipsed the previous all-time production record set in 1973.&nbsp;</li>
<li>
		Overall, oil imports have been falling since 2008, and net imports as a share of total consumption declined from 57 percent in 2008 to 45 percent in 2011 &ndash; the lowest level since 1995.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<p>
	In May of last year, President Obama outlined a series of additional steps to expand domestic oil and gas production as part of his long-term plan to reduce our reliance on foreign oil. More specifically, the President directed the Department of Interior (DOI) to conduct annual lease sales in Alaska&rsquo;s National Petroleum Reserve (NPR-A), speed up the evaluation of oil and gas resources in the mid- and south-Atlantic, develop new incentives for industry to develop unused leases both onshore and offshore, extend drilling leases in the areas of the Gulf impacted by the temporary moratorium following the Deepwater Horizon oil spill, and lease new areas in the Gulf of Mexico.</p>
<p>
	Significant progress has been made in many of these areas. For instance, in December 2011, DOI held the first oil and natural gas lease sale in the Gulf of Mexico since the oil spill. The sale, which covered over 1 million acres, attracted more than $338 million in total bids &ndash; about $100 million more than average for Western Gulf sales over the previous decade. During the same month, DOI held a lease sale in Alaska&rsquo;s NPR-A that generated winning bids of over $3.6 million and covered 17 tracts on over 140,000 acres.</p>
<p>
	The Administration has also taken historic action to reduce our dependence on oil by making our cars and trucks more efficient. In July of last year, the President announced the next phase in the Administration&rsquo;s program to increase fuel economy, which will require a performance equivalent to 54.5 miles per gallon for model year 2017-2025 passenger vehicles. Taken together, the standards established under this Administration span Model Years 2011 to 2025. They will save American families money at the pump, for a total of $1.7 trillion in fuel savings over the life of the program. They will clean up our environment, cutting greenhouse gas emissions by more than 6 billion metric tons over the life of the program, while reducing pollutants like air toxics, cause soot, and smog.</p>
<p>
	These new fuel economy standards will dramatically cut our oil dependence, reducing consumption by an estimated 2.2 million barrels a day in 2025 (eventually reaching more than 4 million barrels a day as the fleet turns over), and saving 12 billion barrels in total over the lifetime of the program. To put that in perspective, it would take a pipeline that carried 700,000 barrels a day nearly 47 years to transport the amount of oil we are saving thanks to these new fuel economy standards.</p>
<p>
	Of course, the Administration has also been intent on developing and deploying clean energy technologies and positioning the United States as the global leader in the clean energy race. The Recovery Act invested more than $90 billion in clean energy, the largest such investment in America&rsquo;s history. Those investments have created hundreds of thousands of jobs and spurred thousands of clean energy projects across the country. For example, the Department of Energy&rsquo;s (DOE) Loan Guarantee Program has already supported more than 40 clean energy projects that will ultimately employ more than 60,000 Americans. And because of Recovery Act investments, we are on track to double non-hydro renewable electricity generation from 2008 levels this year.</p>
<p>
	In short, the Obama Administration&rsquo;s approach to achieving American energy independence has been a comprehensive and sustained effort, with emphasis on boosting domestic energy production, increasing efficiency, and transitioning to cleaner energy sources.</p>
<p>
	But what&rsquo;s abundantly clear is that there are no silver bullets when it comes to this challenge. And the idea, as some in Washington have tried to suggest, that building a pipeline is the ultimate answer to the question of American energy security and job creation is nothing more than a pipe dream. The truth is that just two of the Administration&rsquo;s programs &ndash; the DOE Loan Guarantee Program and the EPA&rsquo;s Mercury and Air Toxics Standards &ndash; will create more than 10 times the amount of jobs generated by the Keystone XL pipeline, which will only generate a few thousand temporary jobs. In terms of reducing America&rsquo;s dependence on oil, the Administration&rsquo;s fuel economy standards alone will save more than twice the amount of oil the Keystone pipeline would deliver. &nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/45">Economy</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/energy-environment">Energy &amp; Environment</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 21:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Heather Zichal</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">113539 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>By the Numbers: 103,785</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/18/numbers-103785</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<div class="embed">
	
<div class="clearfix" id="small-node-embed-image-detail">
  <img src="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/imagecache/embedded_img_small/image/image_file/103785.jpg" alt="103,785" title="103,785" class="imagecache imagecache-embedded_img_small" width="430" height="242" />  </div></div>
<p>
	A total of 103,785 people signed We the People petitions&nbsp;asking the Obama Administration to protect an open and innovative internet.&nbsp;A petition asking President Obama to veto the Stop Online Piracy Act (SOPA) got 51,689 signatures,&nbsp;while&nbsp;52,096 people signed the &ldquo;Stop the E-PARSITE Act&rdquo; petition.</p>
<p>
	Congress is debating a number of bills, including these two,&nbsp;that deal with the issue of online piracy. Today, several web sites joined together in a virtual strike against SOPA and other piracy legislation by shutting down or going dark.</p>
<p>
	Over the weekend, <a href="/blog/2012/01/14/obama-administration-responds-we-people-petitions-sopa-and-online-piracy">the White House responded to the petitions</a>&nbsp;explaining that while online piracy by foreign websites is a serious problem that requires a serious legislative&nbsp;response, attempts to combat it&nbsp;must not reduce freedom of expression, increase cybersecurity risk, or undermine the dynamic, innovative global Internet:</p>
<p class="rteindent1">
	Moving forward, we will continue to work with Congress on a bipartisan basis on legislation that provides new tools needed in the global fight against piracy and counterfeiting, while vigorously defending an open Internet based on the values of free expression, privacy, security and innovation.</p>
<p>
	Read the <a href="https://wwws.whitehouse.gov/petition-tool/response/combating-online-piracy-while-protecting-open-and-innovative-internet">full petition response here</a>, or learn more about <a href="https://wwws.whitehouse.gov/petition-tool/how-why/introduction">We the People</a>, a new platform that allows people to create and sign petitions calling for&nbsp;the Obama Administration to take action on a range of important issues facing our nation.</p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/technology">Technology</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 21:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/3699933&quot;&gt;Megan Slack&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">113521 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Moving Forward and Implementing Health Reform</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/18/moving-forward-and-implementing-health-reform</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	It&rsquo;s been nearly two years since President Obama signed the Affordable Care Act into law. In that time, the law has already made an incredible difference to millions of Americans:</p>
<ul>
<li>
		2.5 million more young adults have health insurance.</li>
<li>
		As of October 2011, more than 2.65 million seniors got a 50 percent discount on their prescription drugs when they hit the donut hole.</li>
<li>
		Insurance companies can no longer drop your coverage when you get sick or put a lifetime cap on the amount of care you can receive.</li>
</ul>
<p>
	Of course, there is more to come in the years ahead. Starting in 2014, consumers in every state will have access to Affordable Insurance Exchanges &ndash; State-based one-stop marketplaces where consumers can choose a private health insurance plan that fits their health needs.&nbsp; Exchanges will offer consumers the same kinds of insurance choices that members of Congress now have. And millions of middle class families will get tax credits to make it easier to buy insurance in the Exchanges.</p>
<p>
	Under the health reform law, States have the first opportunity to set up and manage an Exchange and States are taking action.&nbsp; Today, we released a <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/01-18-12_exchange_report.pdf">new report</a> which finds 28 States have taken important steps toward establishing their own Exchanges. Some of the examples in the report include:</p>
<ul>
<li>
		Alabama Governor Robert Bentley, a physician, issued an Executive Order that created the Alabama Health Insurance Exchange Study Commission on June 2, 2011, which recommended that Alabama establish its own Exchange called the &ldquo;Alabama Health Insurance Marketplace. The legislature, which meets in February, is expected to take up legislation to establish an Exchange, with legislative leaders already indicating their support.</li>
<li>
		Colorado passed a bipartisan bill to establish the independent Colorado Health Insurance Exchange, which was signed into law on June 1, 2011. The Colorado Exchange has started public education about health reform and the Exchange at its website, <a href="http://www.getcoveredco.org">www.getcoveredco.org</a>. Organizations such as the Colorado branch of the National Federation of Independent Business (NFIB) and the Colorado Association of Commerce and Industry have been active participants in creating the small business component of the Exchange.&nbsp;</li>
<li>
		In Nevada, unanimous, bipartisan legislation authorized the Silver State Health Insurance Exchange, which was signed into law by Governor Brian Sandoval on June 16, 2011.&nbsp; Its board has been appointed, executive director named, and application submitted for its next round of funding for building the Exchange.</li>
</ul>
<p>
	Today&rsquo;s report also outlines some of the steps the Department of Health and Human Services has taken to ensure all Americans have access to an Exchange beginning in 2014. These include developing the information technology and business systems necessary to facilitate Exchanges in multiple States.&nbsp; No matter where you live, on January 1, 2014, an Exchange will be up and running.</p>
<p>
	As we move forward, we&rsquo;ll continue to build on our strong partnerships with State leaders nationwide and help ensure all Americans can access high quality, affordable health care and have the security they need and deserve.</p>
<p>
	Nancy-Ann DeParle is Assistant to the President and Deputy Chief of Staff&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
</ul>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/health-care">Health Care</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 14:26:37 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Nancy-Ann DeParle</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">113257 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>The President and First Lady Welcome the St. Louis Cardinals to the White House</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/17/president-and-first-lady-welcome-st-louis-cardinals-white-house</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<div class="embed">
	
<div class="clearfix" id="small-node-embed-image-detail">
  <img src="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/imagecache/embedded_img_small/image/image_file/p011712lj-0177.jpg" alt="President Obama and Mrs. Obama welcome the 2011 World Series Champion St. Louis Cardinals to the White House " title="President Obama and Mrs. Obama welcome the 2011 World Series Champion St. Louis Cardinals to the White House " class="imagecache imagecache-embedded_img_small" width="430" height="287" />  <p>First Lady Michelle Obama reacts to a joke by President Barack Obama as the President and Mrs. Obama welcome the 2011 World Series Champion St. Louis Cardinals to the White House to honor the team and their 2011 World Series victory, in the East Room, Jan. 17, 2012. </p>
</div></div>
<p>
	Today, the President and First Lady hosted the St. Louis Cardinals at the White House to congratulate the team on its World Series win last year.</p>
<p>
	The Cardinals, who President Obama called &ldquo;the greatest comeback team in the history of baseball,&rdquo; made the playoffs after rallying from a ten and a half game deficit with just 31 games left in the regular season. At one point, the team had less than a 4 percent chance of even making the playoffs.</p>
<p>
	The Series itself was an unforgettable one, the <a href="/the-press-office/2012/01/17/remarks-president-and-first-lady-honoring-2011-world-champion-st-louis-c">President said</a>:</p>
<p class="rteindent1">
	Of course, the most memorable moment was Game Six of the World Series.&nbsp; I&rsquo;ve got to say, that has to be one of the best baseball games of all time.&nbsp;Unbelievable game.&nbsp; I will tell you guys, I had a bunch of early-morning stuff the next day, and you kept me up.&nbsp; It was painful waking up the next morning.&nbsp; But what an incredible game.&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/17/president-and-first-lady-welcome-st-louis-cardinals-white-house" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/16">The President</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/18">The First Lady</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/65">Dr. Jill Biden</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/veterans">Veterans</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/joining-forces">Joining Forces</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 02:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/3699933&quot;&gt;Megan Slack&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">113161 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>President Obama Meets with King Abdullah II of Jordan at the White House</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/17/president-obama-meets-king-abdullah-ii-jordan-white-house</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	</p>
<p>
	&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	President Obama today praised His Majesty King Abdullah of Jordan for his leadership in encouraging peace and prosperity throughout the Middle East during what&nbsp;the President described as &quot;an extraordinary time.&quot;</p>
<p>
	Developments <a href="/blog/2011/05/17/president-obama-king-abdullah-ii-jordan-discuss-libya-israel-and-palestine-and-chang">since the two leaders last met</a> include new governments emerging in Egypt, Libya and&nbsp;Tunisia and a transition taking place in Yemen, as well as the current volatility in Syria. Today&#39;s conversation included those topics, and also the importance of&nbsp;both countries&nbsp;continuing to&nbsp;encourage the Palestinians and the Israelis to&nbsp;seriously negotiate&nbsp;a peaceful way forward.</p>
<p>
	The President&nbsp;highlighted the efforts that have been made by&nbsp;King Abdullah and Jordan&#39;s&nbsp;Prime Minister in guiding political reform inside their country.&nbsp;&quot;I think His Majesty has been ahead of the curve in trying to respond to the legitimate concerns and aspirations, both politically and economically, of the Jordanian population,&quot; he said. President Obama said the most pressing issue at the moment is the situation in Syria:</p>
<blockquote><p>
		His Majesty was the first Arab leader to publicly call on President Assad to step down, in the face of the terrible brutality we&rsquo;ve been seeing inside of Syria.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
		I want to thank him for his willingness to stand up.&nbsp; As a consequence, Jordan has been part of an overall Arab League effort to encourage this sort of peaceful transition inside of Syria that is needed.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>
		Unfortunately, we&rsquo;re continuing to see unacceptable levels of violence inside that country, and so we will continue to consult very closely with Jordan to create the kind of international pressure and environment that encourages the current Syrian regime to step aside so that a more democratic process of transition can take place inside of Syria.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>
	&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/16">The President</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/foreign-policy">Foreign Policy</category>
 <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 23:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/475&quot;&gt;Colleen Curtis&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">113101 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>President Obama Meets with the Council on Jobs and Competitiveness</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/17/president-obama-meets-council-jobs-and-competitiveness</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<div class="embed">
	
<div class="clearfix" id="small-node-embed-image-detail">
  <img src="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/imagecache/embedded_img_small/image/image_file/p011712ps-0196.jpg" alt="President Barack Obama meets with the Council on Jobs and Competitiveness " title="President Barack Obama meets with the Council on Jobs and Competitiveness " class="imagecache imagecache-embedded_img_small" width="430" height="287" />  <p>President Barack Obama meets with the Council on Jobs and Competitiveness in the State Dining Room of the White House, Jan. 17, 2012. The council made suggestions for reform of the corporate tax system, expanding and expediting the domestic production of fossil fuels, and new regulatory reforms for business.</p>
</div></div>
<p>
	Today, President Obama convened a meeting of the <a href="http://www.jobs-council.com">Council on Jobs and Competitiveness</a>, a group of 27 leaders from business, labor and academia tasked with providing the President advice on strengthening our nation&rsquo;s economy.</p>
<p>
	Since its first meeting about a year ago, the Council has put forward a host of recommendations that foster growth, competitiveness, innovation, and job creation, both now and for the future. Of the 35 specific recommendations the Council has made that don&rsquo;t require legislative action, President Obama has taken action on 33 of them and his Administration has already implemented 16.</p>
<p>
	Some of the implemented recommendations include proposing new tax rules that encourage businesses <a href="http://edit.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/11/everything-you-need-know-about-insourcing">to invest and create jobs in the United</a> States instead of overseas, <a href="http://edit.whitehouse.gov/blog/2011/11/30/tracking-high-priority-infrastructure-projects">expediting job-creating infrastructure projects</a> across the country, eliminating <a href="http://edit.whitehouse.gov/blog/2011/11/09/save-final-four-and-new-eo-cut-waste">inefficient and burdensome federal regulations</a>, and <a href="http://edit.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/13/making-it-easier-do-business-america">streamlining government</a>.</p>
<p>
	At today&rsquo;s meeting, President Obama praised the Jobs&nbsp;Council for the work they are doing to help our country move forward.</p>
<p class="rteindent1">
	I recognize a lot of these issues are difficult.&nbsp;They&rsquo;ve proven challenging for decades.&nbsp;The good news is on each of these fronts we&rsquo;ve made progress this year.&nbsp;I feel confident in being able to say that every one of the agencies in this government has been focused on how do they improve, get smarter, get better, get faster, become more focused on delivering good value to the end user.&nbsp;And I believe that we&rsquo;ve made genuine progress on all these fronts.&nbsp;We would not have made this progress without this Jobs Council.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	The Jobs Council released a new report in advance of&nbsp;today&#39;s meeting that details recommendations to improve&nbsp;our nation&#39;s&nbsp;long-term competitiveness by investing in our education system, building on our strengths in manufacturing and energy, and reforming our regulatory and corporate tax systems. Read the full report <a href="http://www.jobs-council.com">here</a>.</p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/16">The President</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/45">Economy</category>
 <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 21:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/3699933&quot;&gt;Megan Slack&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">113083 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Announcing the State of the Union Tweetup at the White House</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/17/announcing-state-union-tweetup-white-house</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	On Tuesday, January 24th, President Obama will deliver his State of the Union Address from Capitol Hill. Back at the White House, we&rsquo;re hosting a <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/tweetup">Tweetup</a> where some of our Twitter followers will be invited to watch the President&rsquo;s address live, attend a panel with Administration officials after the speech, and of course tweet!</p>
<p>
	Interested in joining? <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/tweetup">Sign up</a>&nbsp;for your chance to join other&nbsp;<a href="http://www.twitter.com/whitehouse">@WhiteHouse</a>&nbsp;followers to watch the President&rsquo;s annual address to the nation.</p>
<p>
	<a href="https://twitter.com/#!/whitehouse/status/159300887506984960"><img alt="" src="/sites/default/files/sotu-tweetup-screen.png" /></a></p>
<p>
	Apply today! Registration closes at 11:59 p.m. EST on Tuesday, January 17th at&nbsp;<a href="http://www.wh.gov/tweetup">http://www.wh.gov/tweetup</a>. After you sign up, spread the word! Let your followers know that you signed up for the&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/#!/search/%23whtweetup">#WHTweetup</a>&nbsp;and tell us&nbsp;<a href="http://www.twitter.com/whitehouse">@WhiteHouse</a>.</p>
<p>
	Related: Check out blog posts from some of our previous White House Tweetups, including the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2011/12/09/holiday-whtweetup-shine-give-sharetweet">Holiday Open House Tweetup</a>&nbsp;and the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2011/10/13/white-house-tweetup-south-korea-arrival-ceremony-or-totally-worth-it">Republic of Korea Arrival Ceremony Tweetup</a>.</p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/45">Economy</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/technology">Technology</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/additional-issues">Additional Issues</category>
 <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 16:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/45&quot;&gt;Kori Schulman&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">112975 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Watch: First Lady Michelle Obama Previews her &quot;iCarly&quot; Special</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/16/watch-first-lady-michelle-obama-previews-her-icarly-special</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	</p>
<p>
	&nbsp;First Lady Michelle Obama was at the Hayfield Secondary School in Alexandria, Virginia on Friday to preview her special appearance on the&nbsp;hit TV&nbsp;show &quot;iCarly&quot;. The White House joined forces with the Nickelodeon team to teach kids how important friendship and support are to military kids whose parents are deployed for long periods. The show&#39;s lead character, Carly Shay (played by Miranda Cosgrove), is the daughter of an Air Force Colonel currently serving overseas in the military, and two of the&nbsp;cast members&nbsp;grew up&nbsp;in military families.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	The debut of &quot;iMeet the First Lady&quot;&nbsp;on Monday January 16&nbsp;was&nbsp;preceded by a special dedication from the iCarly cast and Mrs. Obama to military families. Immediately following the premiere, Nickelodeon debuted a PSA that features ways kids can show their thanks and support. For more information, visit <a href="http://www.thebighelp.com" title="www.thebighelp.com">www.thebighelp.com</a>.<br />
	&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/18">The First Lady</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/veterans">Veterans</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/joining-forces">Joining Forces</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 21:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/475&quot;&gt;Colleen Curtis&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">112813 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>First Lady Michelle Obama Celebrates Maya Angelo at BET Honors</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/16/first-lady-michelle-obama-celebrates-maya-angelo-bet-honors</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<div class="embed">
	
<div class="clearfix" id="small-node-embed-image-detail">
  <img src="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/imagecache/embedded_img_small/image/image_file/_e5u2041a.jpg" alt="First Lady Michelle Obama applauds Maya Angelo during the BET Awards ceremony" title="First Lady Michelle Obama applauds Maya Angelo during the BET Awards ceremony" class="imagecache imagecache-embedded_img_small" width="430" height="292" />  <p>First Lady Michelle Obama applauds poet Maya Angelou who receives the Literary Arts Award at the BET Honors ceremony at the Warner Theatre in Washington, D.C., Jan. 14, 2012. </p>
</div></div>
<p>
	Michelle Obama was at the BET Honors Saturday night in Washington D.C. to present the Literary Arts award to Maya&nbsp;Angelou, who the First Lady said was one of her &quot;she-roes.&quot; Angelou, who received the <a href="/medal-of-freedom">Presidential Medal of Freedom</a> from President Obama in 2010, is&nbsp;as well known for her work as a civil rights activist as she is an artist, whose prolific body of work includes writing poetry, memoirs, novels and plays. She has also been&nbsp;a producer, actress, historian and filmmaker.</p>
<p>
	Mrs Obama, who told the audience at the historic Warner Theatre that she had been &quot;spellbound&quot; when reading her stories, asked the crowd to&nbsp;honor Angelou&#39;s contributions by following her example:</p>
<blockquote><p>
		Maya Angelou teaches us that it&rsquo;s not enough merely to seek greatness for ourselves.&nbsp;We must help others discover the greatness within themselves.&nbsp;&nbsp;We need to reach down&hellip;and reach out&hellip;and give back&hellip;and lift up others the way Maya has lifted us.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
		&nbsp;That is how we can most truly honor our friend Maya Angelou &ndash; by how we live our lives&hellip;by striving every day to embody the wisdom, and generosity, and radiant love with which she has graced our world.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>
	Related: <a href="/blog/2011/08/26/maya-angelous-abundant-hope">Read the poem Maya Angelou wrote for the dedication of the Martin Luther King Memorial</a></p>
<p>	&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/18">The First Lady</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/2">Civil Rights</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/culture">Culture</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 21:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/475&quot;&gt;Colleen Curtis&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">112807 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Honoring Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Through Service</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/16/honoring-dr-martin-luther-king-jr-through-service</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	Monuments are built to those who change the course of history. It is right and fitting that a memorial to Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. now stands in the heart of our nation&rsquo;s Capital.&nbsp; Even as we renew our understanding of Dr. King&rsquo;s legacy by visiting this beautiful monument; we can honor the legacy of Dr. King by following his example, by serving and volunteering in our communities.</p>
<p>
	Dr. King called service the &ldquo;new definition of greatness.&rdquo; He believed that the work we undertake on behalf of others is the most important work of all. He devoted his life to this notion &ndash; advancing equality, social justice and economic opportunity for all Americans.&nbsp; Dr. King challenged all of us to do our part to build a more perfect union.</p>
<p>
	That is why, for nearly two decades, the nation has marked the life of Dr. King with a <a href="http://mlkday.gov/">national Day of Service</a>. Today, Americans from every state will deliver meals, refurbish schools and community centers, collect food and clothing, sign up mentors, support veterans and military families, and more. Thousands of <a href="http://www.americorps.gov/">AmeriCorps</a>&nbsp;and <a href="http://www.seniorcorps.gov/">Senior Corps</a>&nbsp;members will lend a hand to community-based projects. Individuals and groups, of all ages and backgrounds, will come together &ndash; as Dr. King would have wanted &ndash; in service.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/16/honoring-dr-martin-luther-king-jr-through-service" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/2">Civil Rights</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/service">Service</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/202">African American</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 20:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Cecilia Muoz</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">112759 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>First and Second Families Participate in a National Day of Service </title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/16/first-and-second-families-participate-national-day-service</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<div class="embed">
	
<div class="clearfix" id="small-node-embed-image-detail">
  <img src="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/imagecache/embedded_img_small/image/image_file/p011612ps-0057.jpg" alt="President Obama at Browne" title="President Obama at Browne" class="imagecache imagecache-embedded_img_small" width="430" height="264" />  <p>President Barack Obama delivers remarks at Browne Education Campus in Washington, D.C., before participating in a Martin Luther King, Jr. Day service event with First Lady Michelle Obama and daughter Malia, Jan. 16, 2012. </p>
</div></div>
<p>
	Today, President Obama, the First Lady, and Malia Obama volunteered at a local elementary school as part of a national day of service in honor of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Dr. King, who devoted his life to helping others, once said that &ldquo;everybody can be great, because everybody can serve.&rdquo;</p>
<p>
	Before pitching in to help&nbsp;clean, paint, and organize the school&rsquo;s library, the <a href="/the-press-office/2012/01/16/remarks-president-martin-luther-king-jr-day-service-event">President spoke to other volunteers</a> from Big Brothers, Big Sisters and Greater DC Cares gathered for the event:</p>
<p class="rteindent1">
	There&rsquo;s nobody who can&rsquo;t serve.&nbsp;Nobody who can&rsquo;t help somebody else.&nbsp;And whether you&rsquo;re seven or six or whether you&rsquo;re 76, then you can find opportunities to make an enormous difference in your community.</p>
<p>
	The Vice President and Dr. Jill Biden also joined the millions of Americans participating in service events around the country. They traveled to Philadelphia to take part in the 17th annual Greater Philadelphia Martin Luther King Day of Service, the largest Martin Luther King Jr. Day event in the nation.</p>
<div class="embed">
	
<div class="clearfix" id="small-node-embed-image-detail">
  <img src="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/imagecache/embedded_img_small/image/image_file/v011612dl-0351edit.jpg" alt="Vice President Biden and Dr. Jill Biden participate in MLK Day service event" title="Vice President Biden and Dr. Jill Biden participate in MLK Day service event" class="imagecache imagecache-embedded_img_small" width="430" height="287" />  <p>Vice President Joe Biden and Dr. Jill Biden attend the 17th Annual Martin Luther King Day of Service at Girard College in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, January 16, 2012. </p>
</div></div>
<div class="embed">
	&nbsp;</div>
<div class="embed">
	Read more about how the Obama Administration is honoring Dr. King&#39;s legacy through service:</div>
<div class="embed">
<ul>
<li property="title">
			<a href="/blog/2012/01/16/martin-luther-king-jr-day-honoring-drum-majors-service">On Martin Luther King, Jr. Day, Honoring &quot;Drum Majors for Service,&quot;</a>&nbsp;by Joshua DuBois, Executive Director of the White House Office of Faith-based and Neighborhood Partnerships</li>
<li property="title">
			<a href="/blog/2012/01/16/honoring-dr-martin-luther-king-jr-through-service">Honoring Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Through Service</a>, by Cecilia Mu&ntilde;oz, Director of the White House Domestic Policy Council</li>
</ul>
</div>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/16">The President</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/17">The Vice President</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/18">The First Lady</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/65">Dr. Jill Biden</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/2">Civil Rights</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/service">Service</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 20:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/3699933&quot;&gt;Megan Slack&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">112771 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>On Martin Luther King, Jr. Day, Honoring &quot;Drum Majors for Service&quot;</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/16/martin-luther-king-jr-day-honoring-drum-majors-service</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	Each day in cities and towns across our country, countless Americans are living out Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.&#39;s legacy through their service to others.&nbsp; In his famous speech on The Drum Major Instinct, Dr. King said that it isn&#39;t &quot;a desire to be out front, a desire to lead the parade, a desire to be first&quot; that should define greatness, but rather, &quot;everybody can be great...because everybody can serve.&quot;</p>
<p>
	On this Martin Luther King, Jr. Day and throughout the year, we are proud that the Obama Administration&#39;s Corporation for National and Community Service in conjunction with TheRoot.com will be highlighting &quot;Drum Majors for Service,&quot; volunteers who perform extraordinary everyday acts of service, but who seldom receive recognition. This is an exciting new way to honor those who are living out Dr.&nbsp; King&#39;s legacy each day of their lives.</p>
<p>
	Today, TheRoot.com is highlighting 88 year-old retired Chicago transit worker and ex-Marine Theodore Peters, a true Drum Major for Service. <a href="http://www.theroot.com/views/monfort-point-marines-good-works-follow-mlks-example?wpisrc=root_lightbox">Check it out here</a>, and keep checking back for more stories of Drum Majors for Service.</p>
<p>
	Joshua DuBois serves as Special Assistant to the President and&nbsp;Executive Director of the White House Office of Faith-based and Neighborhood Partnerships.</p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/service">Service</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 19:29:03 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Joshua DuBois</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">112747 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>From the Archives: Dr. Martin Luther King at the White House</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/16/archives-dr-martin-luther-king-white-house</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<div class="embed">
	
<div class="clearfix" id="small-node-embed-image-detail">
  <img src="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/imagecache/embedded_img_small/image/image_file/mlk_leaves_ww.jpg" alt="Martin Luther King, Jr. leaves the West Wing after meeting with President Johnson" title="Martin Luther King, Jr. leaves the West Wing after meeting with President Johnson" class="imagecache imagecache-embedded_img_small" width="430" height="337" />  <p>Martin Luther King, Jr. leaves the West Wing after meeting with President Johnson. August 5, 1965. Abbie Rowe, NPS: National Archive and Records Administration.</p>
</div></div>
<div class="embed">
	
<div class="clearfix" id="small-node-embed-image-detail">
  <img src="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/imagecache/embedded_img_small/image/image_file/mlk_6236.jpg" alt="President Lyndon B. Johnson meets with Civil Rights leaders in the Oval Office" title="President Lyndon B. Johnson meets with Civil Rights leaders in the Oval Office" class="imagecache imagecache-embedded_img_small" width="430" height="288" />  <p>President Lyndon B. Johnson meets with Civil Rights leaders Martin Luther King, Jr., Whitney Young, and James Farmer in the Oval Office. January 18, 1964. .</p>
</div></div>
<p>
	To mark Martin Luther King, Jr.&nbsp;Day, the White House Historical Association has searched their archives and&nbsp;created a slideshow of historic images that show the impact the civil rights leader has had on several administrations.&nbsp;Dr King&#39;s interactions with Presidents Kennedy and&nbsp;Johnson leading up to the Civil Rights Act in 1964, the Voting Rights Act in 1965 and the 1968 Civil Rights Act&nbsp;are well documented, but his first visit to the White House was actually&nbsp;in 1958, when he and other prominent civil rights leaders met with President Dwight Eisenhower. <a href="http://www.whitehousehistory.org/whha_press/index.php/2012/web/martin-luther-king-white-house-photos/">Celebrating Martin Luther King, Jr&#39;s Life and Legacy</a> features images of Dr. King himself at the White House and also includes photos of President Reagan signing the King Holiday Bill in 1983 with Coretta Scott King at his side, and <a href="/blog/2011/10/16/president-obama-martin-luther-king-jr-memorial-dedication-we-will-overcome">President Obama and his family at the national memorial </a>that was dedicated just last year.</p>
<p>
	<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/whitehousehistory/6680245345/">See the slideshow on Flickr</a></p>
<p>
	&nbsp;</p>
<div>
	&nbsp;</div>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/2">Civil Rights</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/475&quot;&gt;Colleen Curtis&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">112615 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>President Obama and Dr. King </title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/16/president-obama-and-dr-king</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<div class="embed">
	
<div class="clearfix" id="small-node-embed-image-detail">
  <img src="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/imagecache/embedded_img_small/image/image_file/6309139069_3f336803a4_b.jpg" alt="President Obama visits MLK memorial at night" title="President Obama visits MLK memorial at night" class="imagecache imagecache-embedded_img_small" width="430" height="645" />  <p>President Barack Obama tours the Martin Luther King, Jr. National Memorial in Washington, D.C., Oct. 14, 2011. </p>
</div></div>
<p>
	It&#39;s been 29 years since President Reagan signed the law to create a national holiday in honor of Martin Luther King, Jr.</p>
<p>
	This year for the first time, however, those who wish to honor Dr. King on the holiday will be able gather in celebration at his memorial on the National Mall in Washington, DC.</p>
<p>
	Seven years ago, then-Senator Obama spoke at the <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2011/10/15/president-obama-dedicate-martin-luther-king-memorial-sunday">groundbreaking</a> for the memorial.</p>
<p>
	And back in October, the President <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2011/10/16/president-obama-martin-luther-king-jr-memorial-dedication-we-will-overcome">spoke at its dedication</a>, where he described the way that Dr. King continues to inspire new generations to work to fulfill his legacy:</p>
<blockquote><p>
		He would not give up, no matter how long it took, because in the smallest hamlets and the darkest slums, he had witnessed the highest reaches of the human spirit; because in those moments when the struggle seemed most hopeless, he had seen men and women and children conquer their fear; because he had seen hills and mountains made low and rough places made plain, and the crooked places made straight and God make a way out of no way.</p>
<p>
		And that is why we honor this man &ndash;- because he had faith in us. And that is why he belongs on this Mall -&ndash; because he saw what we might become. That is why Dr. King was so quintessentially American -- because for all the hardships we&rsquo;ve endured, for all our sometimes tragic history, ours is a story of optimism and achievement and constant striving that is unique upon this Earth. And that is why the rest of the world still looks to us to lead. This is a country where ordinary people find in their hearts the courage to do extraordinary things; the courage to stand up in the face of the fiercest resistance and despair and say this is wrong, and this is right; we will not settle for what the cynics tell us we have to accept and we will reach again and again, no matter the odds, for what we know is possible.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>
	Watch the video of President Obama&#39;s remarks:</p>
<p>
	</p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/16">The President</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/2">Civil Rights</category>
 <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/3336903&quot;&gt;Matt Compton&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">112597 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Obama Administration Responds to We the People Petitions on SOPA and Online Piracy</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/14/obama-administration-responds-we-people-petitions-sopa-and-online-piracy</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	The White House has responded to <a href="https://wwws.whitehouse.gov/petitions#!/petition/veto-sopa-bill-and-any-other-future-bills-threaten-diminish-free-flow-information/g3W1BscR">two</a> <a href="https://wwws.whitehouse.gov/petitions#!/petition/veto-sopa-bill-and-any-other-future-bills-threaten-diminish-free-flow-information/g3W1BscR">petitions</a> about legislative approaches to combat online piracy. In their response, Victoria Espinel, Intellectual Property Enforcement Coordinator at Office of Management and Budget, Aneesh Chopra, U.S. Chief Technology Officer, and Howard Schmidt, Special Assistant to the President and Cybersecurity Coordinator for National Security Staff stress that the&nbsp;<a href="https://wwws.whitehouse.gov/petition-tool/response/combating-online-piracy-while-protecting-open-and-innovative-internet">important task of protecting intellectual property online must not threaten an open and innovative internet</a>.</p>
<div>
<blockquote><h3>
			<a href="https://wwws.whitehouse.gov/petition-tool/response/combating-online-piracy-while-protecting-open-and-innovative-internet">Combating Online Piracy while Protecting an Open and Innovative Internet</a></h3>
<div>
			By Victoria Espinel, Aneesh Chopra, and Howard Schmidt</div>
<div>
			&nbsp;</div>
<div>
			Thanks for taking the time to sign this petition. Both your words and actions illustrate the importance of maintaining an open and democratic Internet.</div>
<div>
			&nbsp;</div>
<div>
			Right now, Congress is debating a few pieces of legislation concerning the very real issue of online piracy, including the Stop Online Piracy Act (SOPA), the PROTECT IP Act, and the Online Protection and Digital ENforcement Act (OPEN). We want to take this opportunity to tell you what the Administration will support&mdash;and what we will not support. Any effective legislation should reflect a wide range of stakeholders, including everyone from content creators to the engineers that build and maintain the infrastructure of the Internet.</div>
<div>
			&nbsp;</div>
<div>
			While we believe that online piracy by foreign websites is a serious problem that requires a serious legislative response, we will not support legislation that reduces freedom of expression, increases cybersecurity risk, or undermines the dynamic, innovative global Internet.</div>
<div>
			&nbsp;</div>
<div>
			Any effort to combat online piracy must guard against the risk of online censorship of lawful activity and must not inhibit innovation by our dynamic businesses large and small. Across the globe, the openness of the Internet is increasingly central to innovation in business, government, and society and it must be protected. To minimize this risk, new legislation must be narrowly targeted only at sites beyond the reach of current U.S. law, cover activity clearly prohibited under existing U.S. laws, and be effectively tailored, with strong due process and focused on criminal activity. Any provision covering Internet intermediaries such as online advertising networks, payment processors, or search engines must be transparent and designed to prevent overly broad private rights of action that could encourage unjustified litigation that could discourage startup businesses and innovative firms from growing.</div>
<div>
			&nbsp;
</div></blockquote></div><p><a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/14/obama-administration-responds-we-people-petitions-sopa-and-online-piracy" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/technology/we-people">We the People</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/economy/innovations">Innovations</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/45">Economy</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/technology">Technology</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/201">Tech and New Media</category>
 <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2012 13:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/42&quot;&gt;Macon Phillips&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">112699 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Weekly Address: Helping American Businesses Succeed</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/14/weekly-address-helping-american-businesses-succeed</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	President Obama discusses steps he&#39;s taking to ensure that more goods and products stamped &quot;Made in America&quot; are sold in the United States and around the world.</p>
<p>
	</p>
<p>
	<a href="/the-press-office/2012/01/13/weekly-address-helping-american-businesses-succeed">Transcript</a> | <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/WeeklyAddress/2012/011412-TRQAMX/011412_WeeklyAddress.mp4">Download mp4</a> | <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/WeeklyAddress/2012/011412-TRQAMX/011412_WeeklyAddress.mp3">Download mp3</a></p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/16">The President</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/38">Weekly Address</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/45">Economy</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/econ-business-america">Econ. Business in America</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/cms-only-terms/economy">Economy</category>
 <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2012 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/3699933&quot;&gt;Megan Slack&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">112657 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Higher Education and the Middle Class Bargain</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/13/higher-education-and-middle-class-bargain</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<p>
	</p>
<p>
	The Vice President visited high schools in Columbus, Ohio and Doylestown, Pennsylvania this week to highlight our Administration&rsquo;s efforts to make college more affordable for all Americans. He was joined by Secretary of Education Arne Duncan and Senator Sherrod Brown in Ohio, and by Deputy Secretary of Education Tony Miller in Pennsylvania.&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	Speaking at Lincoln High School in Columbus, Ohio on Thursday, the Vice President called for the &ldquo;bargain with the middle class&rdquo; to be restored: &ldquo;There was a bargain in place for last 50 years that if you worked hard, you played by the rules, you helped increase productivity in America, you got a piece of the action.&nbsp; You benefited.&rdquo;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>
	President Obama and Vice President Biden believe that making college affordable is an essential part of restoring that bargain. Our Administration has increased the maximum Pell Grant award by more than $800 and created the $2,500 per year American Opportunity Tax Credit. Even with more generous grants and tax credits, most college students borrow money to pay for school, so we are also limiting federal student loan payments to 10% of discretionary income.&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/13/higher-education-and-middle-class-bargain" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/17">The Vice President</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/45">Economy</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/admin/category/issue-tag/education">Education</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 23:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Brian Levine</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">112663 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>From the Archives: President Reagan Designates Martin Luther King, Jr. Day a Federal Holiday</title>
 <link>http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/01/13/archives-president-reagan-designates-martin-luther-king-jr-day-federal-holiday</link>
 <description><![CDATA[<div class="embed">
	
<div class="clearfix" id="small-node-embed-image-detail">
  <img src="http://www.whitehouse.gov/sites/default/files/imagecache/embedded_img_small/image/image_file/reagan_mlk.jpg" alt="Reagan signs MLK Day legislation" title="Reagan signs MLK Day legislation" class="imagecache imagecache-embedded_img_small" width="430" height="343" />  <p>President Ronald Reagan signs legislation to create a federal holiday honoring Martin Luther King, Jr. in the Rose Garden of the White House on November 2, 1983.</p>
</div></div>
<p>
	Only three people have a national holiday observed in their honor: Christopher Columbus, George Washington, and Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.</p>
<p>
	Martin Luther King, Jr. Day, celebrated on the third Monday of January each year, marks the birthday of the civil rights leader and nonviolent activist. The call for a national holiday to honor Dr. King&rsquo;s legacy began soon after his assassination in 1968&mdash;U.S. Rep. John Conyers (D-MI) introduced legislation to establish the holiday <a href="http://www.archives.gov/eeo/special-observances/#jan">just four days after Dr. King was killed</a>, but Congress took no action on the bill.</p>
<p>
	In the years that followed, millions of people signed petitions in support of the holiday. Coretta Scott King testified before Congress multiple times, calling for a federally recognized day to honor the life and work of her late husband. In 1980, <a href="http://www.nps.gov/features/malu/feat0002/wof/Stevie_Wonder.htm">Stevie Wonder released a song, &ldquo;Happy Birthday</a>,&rdquo; which became both a hit and a rallying cry for supporters of the holiday, and civil rights marches in Washington in 1982 and 1983 only served to amplify their mission.</p>
<p>
	A bill to establish the holiday successfully passed through both houses of Congress in 1983, and President Reagan signed it into law on November 20 of that year. The first Martin Luther King, Jr. Day was <a href="http://www.archives.gov/eeo/special-observances/#jan">celebrated in 1986</a>.</p>
<p>
	Many Americans now honor Dr. King&rsquo;s legacy by participating in a community service event in their own neighborhood andhis vision of service and volunteering is more critical than ever during this economic recovery. President Obama has called on the nation to participate in a service event in their own community this Monday, January 16, 2012.</p>
<p>
	The First and Second Families, numerous members of the President&rsquo;s cabinet, and thousands of other Americans across the country have committed to serve, and you can, too. Visit <a href="http://mlkday.gov/">MLKDay.gov</a>&nbsp;to find a service opportunity in your neighborhood and learn more about the Martin Luther King Day of Service.</p>
]]></description>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/1">White House</category>
 <category domain="http://www.whitehouse.gov/taxonomy/term/2">Civil Rights</category>
 <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 22:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>&lt;a href=&quot;/author-detail/3699933&quot;&gt;Megan Slack&lt;/a&gt;</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">112591 at http://www.whitehouse.gov</guid>
</item>
  </channel>
</rss>